

# **Andrew Love**

Lead Infrastructure Engineer and Developer Advocate

**♀** London, UK

#### **DETAILS**

41 Doughty Street London WC1N 2LF

**4** +44 (0)7785 953757

linkedin.com/in/loveaj

Ioveaj.io

### **PROFILE**

I am a passionate geek with an innate curiosity about using software to build better systems for business and better products for users. I have over 30 years of experience in Fintech, ranging from software development to DevOps to on-premise and cloud infrastructure. I have guided teams as the product manager for the FNZ/JHC FIGARO web, mobile and REST API product set. I have championed the use of open source software and the engagement in OSS and DevOps communities. As a partner/director I have helped create a successful Fintech company and experienced its growth phases from a start-up of 10 people to its current 250+ employees. All of this, from day one, has been done in close collaboration with clients. I have extensive experience in BA, consultant and pre-sales roles.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Infrastructure Architect and Consultant @ FNZ/JHC Systems Ltd $\,$

2001 - 2019

Design and implementation of infrastructure for on-premise, managed service (private cloud) and public cloud deployments of the FNZ/JHC FIGARO wealth management system. Covering networking, server specifications, 3<sup>rd</sup>-party communications, security, virtualisation, high availability, replication and disaster recovery. Technology reviews and upgrades to increase availability, scalability and drive down total cost of ownership.

Supporting DevOps practices through the introduction of Ansible automation, Docker, Kubernetes container management and the insertion of Ops into development projects.

Pre-sales support covering infrastructure and product integrations.

### Product Manager @ FNZ/JHC Systems Ltd

2001 - 2019

Product manager responsible for:

- FNZ/JHC FIGARO web portal for retail & wealth management clients.
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO mobile app for wealth management clients.
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO REST API.

Roadmap strategy and technical/UX/UI design governance, client and market research, project funding.

### IT Manager @ JHC Systems Ltd

2007 - 2012

Responsible for all internal IT including the design and implementation of LANs, WAN, network security, data centre co-location, data backup, disaster recovery, telephony, office moves, desktop standardisation, email, document management, IBM Power Systems and vendor management.

### Senior Developer and Consultant @ JHC Systems Ltd

1991 - 2000

JHC FIGARO stockbroking and wealth management system, specialising in  $3^{\rm rd}$ -party systems integration.

Java, Delphi and RPG

### **Developer and Consultant @ JHC Systems Ltd**

1988 - 1990

JHC Legal Accounting system and JHC FIGARO stockbroking and wealth management system.

**RPG** 

### **SKILLS**

#### **Software Architecture**

- Web and mobile apps
- APIs
- Distributed, complex systems and integrations
- Containers and container management systems
- Cloud-native applications (micro-services, service meshes)

### Software Development Life Cycle

- Agile software development (Scrum, Kanban)
- Source control (GIT) and release strategies
- CI/CD (Jenkins)

#### Infrastructure

- Physical servers (Intel, AMD, IBM Power Systems)
- Virtualisation (VMWare, QEMU/KVM/libvirt, VirtualBox, Parallels)
- Storage (JBOD, RAID, LVM, GlusterFS)
- Networking (LAN, WAN, VPN, Software Defined Networks)
- Security (Network firewalls, application firewalls, AuthN, AuthZ)
- Operating systems (RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu, MacOS, MS Windows, IBM i)

### Public, private and hybrid clouds

- Kubernetes (RedHat Openshift, GCP+GKE, KubeSpray)
- Docker, Docker Compose, Docker Swarm
- OpenStack

### **Telemetry**

- Loggging (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana/Grafana, Splunk)
- Tracing (Zipkin)
- Metrics (Dropwizard, Prometheus, Grafana)
- Monitoring (Nagios, Grafana)

### **DevOps**

- Ansible
- CI/CD (Jenkins)

### Languages

- Java
- Python
- Javascript
- Bash
- HTML/CSS

### **Product Management**

- Web apps
- Mobile apps
- REST APIs

### **Client Engagement**

- On-site support and troubleshooting
- Pre-sales support and consultancy
- Software design consultancy and business analysis
- Infrastructure consultancy
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO system implementations
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO system integration projects

### **EDUCATION**

### **University of Salford**

1984 - 1988

1st BSc (Hons) Applied Physics with Electronics

### **PASSIONS**

Concept design

Interface design

Open Source Software (OSS) and OSS communities

Contemporary art

Science (historical and contemporary)